<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DayEntry xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="urn:newtelligence-com:dasblog:runtime:data">
  <Date>2008-12-14T17:00:00-07:00</Date>
  <Entries>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;This looks very interesting. (from their site)&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;blockquote&gt;   &lt;p&gt;ELMAH (Error Logging Modules and Handlers) is an application-wide error logging facility that is completely pluggable. It can be dynamically added to a running &lt;a href="http://www.asp.net/"&gt;ASP.NET&lt;/a&gt; web application, or even all ASP.NET web applications on a machine, without any need for re-compilation or re-deployment. &lt;/p&gt;    &lt;p&gt;Once ELMAH has been dropped into a running web application and configured appropriately, you get the following facilities without changing a single line of your code: &lt;/p&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;     &lt;li&gt;Logging of nearly all unhandled exceptions. &lt;/li&gt;      &lt;li&gt;A web page to remotely view the entire log of recoded exceptions. &lt;/li&gt;      &lt;li&gt;A web page to remotely view the full details of any one logged exception. &lt;/li&gt;      &lt;li&gt;In many cases, you can review the original &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yellow_Screen_of_Death#ASP.NET"&gt;yellow screen of death&lt;/a&gt; that ASP.NET generated for a given exception, even with &lt;tt&gt;customErrors&lt;/tt&gt; mode turned off. &lt;/li&gt;      &lt;li&gt;An e-mail notification of each error at the time it occurs. &lt;/li&gt;      &lt;li&gt;An RSS feed of the last 15 errors from the log. &lt;/li&gt;      &lt;li&gt;A number of backing storage implementations for the log, including in-memory, &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/sql/"&gt;Microsoft SQL Server&lt;/a&gt; and several &lt;a href="http://groups.google.com/group/elmah/files"&gt;contributed by the community&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;   &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I haven’t use it yet, but it really sounds like something that I see myself incorporating into my tool box. You can download it from &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/elmah/" target="_blank"&gt;Google code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2008-12-15T12:51:00-07:00</Created>
      <Modified>2008-12-14T22:39:52.8672869-07:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>9265c5e7-1769-46b1-a8b1-f8cdebe7f6b6</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>ELMAH error handler for asp.net applications</Title>
      <Categories>General;Tools</Categories>
      <Author>hgarcia</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
      <Latitude xsi:nil="true" />
      <Longitude xsi:nil="true" />
    </Entry>
  </Entries>
</DayEntry>