<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DayEntry xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="urn:newtelligence-com:dasblog:runtime:data">
  <Date>2008-12-19T17:00:00-07:00</Date>
  <Entries>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;In my machine at work I can’t install ASP.NET MVC (it installs but fails to install the project templates, I don’t know why and I haven’t had time to look into it). When I installed Sharp Architecture everything went well, but running the project template yields and error. I was doing this at a Starbuck’s, trying to build a proof of concept and was a bit frustrating. I was sure that the culprit was related to the error I had installing MVC.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Last night I run across a thread entitled &lt;a href="http://groups.google.com/group/sharp-architecture/browse_thread/thread/bd62213055e35bea?hl=en" target="_blank"&gt;Removed dependency on installed ASP.NET MVC Beta&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a href="http://groups.google.com/group/sharp-architecture?hl=en" target="_blank"&gt;Sharp Architecture discussion group&lt;/a&gt;. In this thread in reference to a post by &lt;a href="http://codebetter.com/blogs/kyle.baley/archive/2008/12/12/asp-net-mvc-and-the-gaaak.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;Kyle Baley&lt;/a&gt; where he mentions the same problem, &lt;a href="http://devlicio.us/blogs/billy_mccafferty/default.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;Billy McCafferty&lt;/a&gt; notes that the reference to the MVC templates have been removed on the trunk.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Kyle’s post mentions a few alternative solutions and further down the thread there is a discussion about losing the item templates for the MVC project and Replacing them with ReSharper templates.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I will suggest just that you can also use Visual Studio Item Templates, &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/tsyyf0yh(VS.80).aspx" target="_blank"&gt;creating them yourself&lt;/a&gt; in case you don’t have ReSharper.&amp;#160; You can see an example on building this item templates in this old post of mine &lt;a href="http://blog.dynamicprogrammer.com/2008/05/18/NantBuildScriptsTemplateForVisualStudio.aspx"&gt;Nant build scripts template for Visual Studio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2008-12-20T05:56:00-07:00</Created>
      <Modified>2008-12-18T22:57:08.8454148-07:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>39e90e60-79aa-4772-b00a-d581f3f7ab78</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>Sharp Architecture project template in a machine without ASP.NET MVC Beta installed</Title>
      <Categories>Programming;Tools</Categories>
      <Author>hgarcia</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
      <Latitude xsi:nil="true" />
      <Longitude xsi:nil="true" />
    </Entry>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;At least two really good post today about the future RC1 for the ASP.NET MVC framework. &lt;a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2008/12/19/asp-net-mvc-design-gallery-and-upcoming-view-improvements-with-the-asp-net-mvc-release-candidate.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;Scott Gu&lt;/a&gt; has a very detailed post with some of the new features expected in RC1. &lt;a href="http://haacked.com/archive/2008/12/19/a-little-holiday-love-from-the-asp.net-mvc-team.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;Phil Haack&lt;/a&gt; talks about the delay and the improvements with the Views.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Scaffolding, views without code behind (yeah!), new HtmlHelper&amp;lt;TModel&amp;gt; and AjaxHelper&amp;lt;TModel&amp;gt; types to build strongly typed HTML and AJAX helpers (this should remove the need for magic string.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The feature that got most exited was the changes to the Views, no code behind is, IMHO the way the Views should be. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I can’t wait to put my hands in this release.&lt;/p&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2008-12-20T15:48:00-07:00</Created>
      <Modified>2008-12-19T21:17:21.5373882-07:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>80c0841e-2e14-4f33-9cfd-5be93582f8dc</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>ASP.NET MVC RC 1 coming next January.</Title>
      <Categories>Frameworks;Programming</Categories>
      <Author>hgarcia</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
      <Latitude xsi:nil="true" />
      <Longitude xsi:nil="true" />
    </Entry>
  </Entries>
</DayEntry>