<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DayEntry xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="urn:newtelligence-com:dasblog:runtime:data">
  <Date>2008-05-12T17:00:00-07:00</Date>
  <Entries>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;p&gt;Following to yesterday presentation at the TVBUG, Scott Hanselman gave the keynote on &lt;a href="http://astoria.mslivelabs.com/"&gt;Data Services&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/davidebb/default.aspx"&gt;Dynamic Data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both of this two (products?, projects?, solutions?) are focus in different ways to provide access to your data.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Dynamic data allows you to very easy and quick create all the admin forms for a given database (similar but different to the scaffolding on Rails).&lt;br&gt;The main difference is that there is not code generated for the pages you see.&lt;br&gt;All the code is based on templates and every rendered field is based on templates as well, so you can very easily change the way a field will render.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Data services was already covered in my previous post about Scott's presentation at the TVBUG.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2008-05-13T10:29:27-07:00</Created>
      <Modified>2008-12-14T22:12:06.4103507-07:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>40</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>DevTeach day 1 - Scott Hanselman keynote</Title>
      <Categories>General</Categories>
      <Author>hgarcia</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
      <Latitude xsi:nil="true" />
      <Longitude xsi:nil="true" />
    </Entry>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/"&gt;Scott Hanselmann&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/bethmassi/"&gt;Beth Massi&lt;/a&gt; both gave a presentation today at the &lt;a href="http://www.tvbug.com/"&gt;Toronto Visual Basic User Group&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/netframework/aa904594.aspx"&gt;LINQ &lt;/a&gt;in general.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beth created a windows form app using VB.NET, &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb308960.aspx"&gt;LINQ to XML&lt;/a&gt; to and &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb425822.aspx"&gt;LINQ to SQL&lt;/a&gt; to read data from three different feeds and populate a simple database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She presented some nice queries and gloat a little bit on some of the goodness of LINQ on VB, making some good spirited jokes for the C sharp guys in the audience (like myself).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scott give us a nice preview of &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb906063.aspx"&gt;Astoria&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="http://astoria.mslivelabs.com/"&gt;ADO.NET Data Services&lt;/a&gt;) and show up some of the internal working, (how the magic happen as he put i). I really like that part of the presentation since I really like to know what's going when code is generated by the IDE.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data Services allow you to present some entities as REST services, it return both XML (Atom) and Json. Data Services comes in the new VS 08 and .NET 3.5 SP1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will going to check it out as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2008-05-12T20:22:38-07:00</Created>
      <Modified>2008-12-14T22:33:10.6760849-07:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>39</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>Linqy batch of goodness - TVBUG meeting with Scott Hanselmann</Title>
      <Categories>General;Programming</Categories>
      <Author>hgarcia</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
      <Latitude xsi:nil="true" />
      <Longitude xsi:nil="true" />
    </Entry>
  </Entries>
</DayEntry>