<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DayEntry xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="urn:newtelligence-com:dasblog:runtime:data">
  <Date>2008-12-10T17:00:00-07:00</Date>
  <Entries>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;A few days ago was announced the date for the Professional Developers Conference 2009 or PDC. You can see the &lt;a href="http://channel9.msdn.com/posts/PDCNews/Announcing-PDC2009/" target="_blank"&gt;announcement&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.ustechsregister.com/pdc09mailinglist/main.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;subscribe&lt;/a&gt; to the mailing list. The conference will be on November 17-20, 2009 in Los Angeles, California.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: The page for the mailing list has the PDC 2008 logo, but that’s ok.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;div class="wlWriterEditableSmartContent" id="scid:0767317B-992E-4b12-91E0-4F059A8CECA8:ab1fdb0c-0bfa-43fc-a5ff-e91fd86b6e12" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; display: inline; float: none;"&gt;Technorati Tags: &lt;a href="http://technorati.com/tags/PDC+2009" rel="tag"&gt;PDC 2009&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2008-12-11T16:08:32.227-07:00</Created>
      <Modified>2008-12-14T22:17:39.7079783-07:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>d1f396af-e2a0-48cd-bdc2-b4c66be030ef</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>PDC 2009 dates and mailing list.</Title>
      <Categories>General</Categories>
      <Author>hgarcia</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
      <Latitude xsi:nil="true" />
      <Longitude xsi:nil="true" />
    </Entry>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;YAGNI or “You ain’t gonna need it”, is great. It keep people like me to over design systems. Now, every time that I start to write some piece of code I always have that said in mind. You will be surprised how many times I found myself telling me, YAGNI. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Although, sometimes, this can be misused. Sometimes this “rule” may be used as an excuse to write tightly couple systems, difficult to maintain in the long run. I know that this is not the spirit of “YAGNI”, but a week ago somebody said that to me when we were talking about the importance of programming against interfaces. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;So let me tell you what my own interpretation of YAGNI is. Do not create that cool feature that nobody requested, but design your system in a way that when (or if) somebody request that cool feature, you will be able to implement it without rewriting the whole system.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;So what we do? Well, just apply solid OO design principles. Make your system extensible. This is not as difficult as it sounds. Design from the get go a modular system. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Program against interfaces. This will facilitate the use of Dependency Injection to reduce friction. You should make sure that different compilation units do not depend on each other. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Practice Test First (TDD or BDD) or at least have a good test suite in place so later on you can change your system with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Make sure that you put your business rules in the right place and not scattered all over your system. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Do not be afraid of aggressively refactor your code to make it more readable, even when the feature works, refactoring your code to make it extensible is not a violation of YAGNI.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;div class="wlWriterEditableSmartContent" id="scid:0767317B-992E-4b12-91E0-4F059A8CECA8:64cd351b-8572-465d-bfbf-cb62ac68b15f" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; display: inline; float: none;"&gt;Technorati Tags: &lt;a href="http://technorati.com/tags/Development" rel="tag"&gt;Development&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="http://technorati.com/tags/YAGNI" rel="tag"&gt;YAGNI&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="http://technorati.com/tags/Agile" rel="tag"&gt;Agile&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="http://technorati.com/tags/TDD" rel="tag"&gt;TDD&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="http://technorati.com/tags/DI" rel="tag"&gt;DI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2008-12-10T22:02:32.701-07:00</Created>
      <Modified>2008-12-14T22:25:41.2921604-07:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>972d6190-b3e4-4c21-a89f-bcd3f0d99a96</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>YAGNI it’s not a excuse for badly designed applications.</Title>
      <Categories>General</Categories>
      <Author>hgarcia</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
      <Latitude xsi:nil="true" />
      <Longitude xsi:nil="true" />
    </Entry>
  </Entries>
</DayEntry>