<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DayEntry xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="urn:newtelligence-com:dasblog:runtime:data">
  <Date>2009-10-15T17:00:00-07:00</Date>
  <Entries>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;p&gt;Some time ago I heard about the intent of putting together a package manager for .net ala &lt;a href="http://docs.rubygems.org/" target="_blank"&gt;gems&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://pear.php.net/" target="_blank"&gt;pear&lt;/a&gt;. I wasn’t aware that this project was actually under way. The name of the project, &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/hornget/" target="_blank"&gt;Horn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Please check the links in the project home page on how to get started with &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/hornget/" target="_blank"&gt;Horn&lt;/a&gt;. It’s very simple and actually works as promised. One thing you need to remember is that you will have to install a subversion client and a &lt;a href="http://git-scm.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; client for Horn to check out the source code from the projects you want to build.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I had two issues in my &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/windows/windows-7/" target="_blank"&gt;Win7&lt;/a&gt; machine, where I tested. The first issue is related to &lt;a href="http://git-scm.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; really and not to Horn and/or &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/windows/windows-7/" target="_blank"&gt;Win7&lt;/a&gt;. Make sure that you have the path to your git.cmd into the PATH of your computer.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It’s usually %PROGRAMFILES%/Git/cmd, if you don’t when trying to do a horn –install on a project using &lt;a href="http://git-scm.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.castleproject.org/container/index.html" target="_blank"&gt;Windsor&lt;/a&gt; (the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inversion_of_control" target="_blank"&gt;Ioc&lt;/a&gt; container used by &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/hornget/" target="_blank"&gt;Horn&lt;/a&gt;) will throw an exception. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The other issue seems to be a concurrency issue when trying to read a Temp file. Not sure how this files is been created just yet. This happens while trying to build complex projects like &lt;a href="http://www.codeplex.com/MVCContrib" target="_blank"&gt;MvcContrib&lt;/a&gt;. Re-issuing the install command will “resume” the build. It took me three attempts to build &lt;a href="http://www.codeplex.com/MVCContrib" target="_blank"&gt;MvcContrib&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Even with this issue (that may not be a &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/hornget/" target="_blank"&gt;Horn&lt;/a&gt; issue at all) I think that this is a very important project for the .Net community. It makes building this complex projects with all the dependencies a routine task. You don’t have to spend hours tracking down the project, the source code and pray that everything builds and works well together.&lt;/p&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2009-10-15T19:19:19.3224801-07:00</Created>
      <Modified>2009-10-15T19:19:19.3224801-07:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>aa16764e-8120-4cd7-afea-e5ae1adc66fa</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>Horn: First Impressions</Title>
      <Categories>Frameworks;Programming;Tools</Categories>
      <Author>hgarcia</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
      <Latitude xsi:nil="true" />
      <Longitude xsi:nil="true" />
    </Entry>
  </Entries>
</DayEntry>