<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DayEntry xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="urn:newtelligence-com:dasblog:runtime:data">
  <Date>2009-09-09T17:00:00-07:00</Date>
  <Entries>
    <Entry>
      <Content>I think this has been the longest hiatus since I started the blog. I have been busy with life, talking some time of, finishing tons of renovations at home and re-focusing my priorities from a development point of view.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I'm looking forward to renew the posting pretty soon with the usual frecuency of one to two post a week.&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2009-09-09T21:13:43.3131596-07:00</Created>
      <Modified>2009-09-09T21:13:43.3131596-07:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>d5078865-689f-4e3b-accd-2fb2d0f2fc19</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>More than a month without posting - wow!</Title>
      <Categories>General</Categories>
      <Author>hgarcia</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
      <Latitude xsi:nil="true" />
      <Longitude xsi:nil="true" />
    </Entry>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;p&gt;Last week I was reading &lt;a href="http://www.valuablecode.com/2009/09/how-code-retreat-taught-me-to-be.html" target="_blank"&gt;Alistair’s post about the Toronto Code Retreat&lt;/a&gt;. I was planning to attend but I had plane tickets for the same day so I miss the opportunity, what I regret. In that post Alistair refers to the book &lt;a href="http://www.pragprog.com/titles/cfcar2/the-passionate-programmer" target="_blank"&gt;The Passionate Programmer&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="http://chadfowler.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Chad Fowler&lt;/a&gt;. Next you know, I was ordering the book from Amazon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Saturday I pick it up from the post office and next day I was sitting in the backyard going through the pages while preparing a BBQ. The book reads fast. Its divided in Five sections and each section consist of a series of very short chapters that, most of the time, are no more than two or three pages .&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I found that I’m doing a lot of the things that Chad recommends and I identify myself with some of the situations he mentions in the book. I particularly enjoyed the section about marketing yourself something I’m not good at doing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are a few chapters that I market down to re-read later on, not because they are so deep that need a re-write, but mostly because are the ones that talk to my weakness and the stuff that I need to remind myself to work on to improve.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sparkled along the book there are easies from some renowned programmers on how they build their careers. They make for an enjoyable and fun read, and provide a break from the more “to the point” writing that Chad uses.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;All in all a very enjoyable book that can provide some help on achieving exactly what the tag line for the book is “creating a remarkable career in software development”. &lt;/p&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2009-09-10T04:25:51.6795094-07:00</Created>
      <Modified>2009-09-10T04:25:51.6795094-07:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>10a36d05-75a6-44c3-a413-e10138b44001</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>The Passionate Programmer - Book review.</Title>
      <Categories>Books</Categories>
      <Author>hgarcia</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
      <Latitude xsi:nil="true" />
      <Longitude xsi:nil="true" />
    </Entry>
  </Entries>
</DayEntry>